GERMAIN AKENJI CHI

2302 Londin Lane East, Saint Paul, MN 55119 ● Cell: (612) 669-3964 ● Email: germainchi43@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Dedicated, hardworking and highly motivated computer Science graduate with about 3 years of proven Information Technology, leadership and organizational skills. Currently seeking to apply my abilities and skills in a way that is mutually beneficial to both myself and employer thereby allowing for future growth and advancement.

My goal is to earn a position as a contributing member of a highly motivated web design team, Striving to build robust, creative, and purpose-built applications that exceed client and employer expectations.

SKILLS PROFILE

- <u>Computer Software & Language:</u> C, Javascript, Angular js and Ionic Framework, Bootstrap, Foundation, Lansweeper, Bomgar, Microsoft Exchange Admin, Kaseya, Microsoft CRM, Team viewer, Library connect devices, API, liber8connect, quick connect, java, MATLAB, Back end Development, Front end developer, Microsoft Azure cloud computing, HTML, CSS.
- Relevant Coursework: Programming (C, Javascript, Angular js and Ionic), Algorithms and Data Structures, Network Architecture, Communications Protocols, Digital Signal Processing, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Database systems, Morphological Filters, Coding Theory, Internet Technologies, Web Design
- <u>International experience:</u> International residence and travel, proficient in French language

EDUCATION & TRAINING

University of Information Science and Technology, "Saint Paul the Apostle." *Bachelor of Science*

Ohrid, Macedonia

October 2012- January 2017 GPA: 3.2/4.0

- Concentration: Communication Networks and Security
- Thesis: Morphological Cancellation of Binary Noise ParticleUtilization of image software and morphological operations to cancel noise effects on an image
- Coding Bootcamp at the University of Minnesota, studying Full Stack web designing Projected: May 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MAXIMUS St. Paul, MN

IT Tech Support

November 2018-Present

- Knowledge of systems software sufficient to determine if a malfunction is in the hardware or in the software
- Analyze code to find and correct problems, .
- Develop and maintain integrations, feeds and related batch processes
- Edit configuration code lines to better adopt to clients' specification
- Using Lansweeper for network and server management for some software applications.
- Provide application support for newly developed applications and provide feedback to developers.
- installing and deploy Windows based computers
- Control VDI environment granting access and creating user accounts.
- Writing and creating documentation for knowledge base and new employee training.

BIBLIOTHECA Oakdale, MN

IT Support Specialist

June 2018-Present

 Troubleshoot and develop technical solutions related to software and system errors for field engineers, technicians and customers

- Write and implement scripts to optimize functionality of systems
- Monitor devices' performance using library connect for device status, provide permissions, create organizations and reconfigure software settings
- Maintain systems capability by testing computer components
- Maximize use of hardware and software by training users, interpreting instructions, answering questions
- Place hardware and software into production by establishing connections, and entering necessary commands

University of Information Science and Technology "Saint Paul the Apostle" Helpdesk Student Worker

Ohrid, Macedonia October 2013- February 2014

- Assisted university students, faculty, and employees with varying problems with their PC, Mac, or Linux system via telephone, e-mail, or walk-ins to university IT help desk
- Worked with other student workers to wipe, rebuild, and install specific software, hardware, and or operating systems for laptops and desktops

Societe Nationale de Raffinage SA (SONARA) Limbe, Cameroon Information Technology Security Consultant Intern June - October 2012

- Planned and performed security measures to prevent breach and access to computer systems and data from external sources
- Maintained computer systems with latest technologies, installed and updated firewall systems to prevent unwarranted access

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

 Organization of American States (OAS) Scholarship Recipient CodeFest Participant on behalf of University of Information Science and Technology. Ace Award Winner and the Golden Wrench Award 	2012-2017 2020
LEADEARSHIP AND COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT	
• International Student Organization President	2015-2017
• Red Cross Ohrid Macedonia Volunteer	2016-2017
 Cultural Exchange Program Summer Work and Travel Participant 	2015–2016
 University of Information Science & Technology Student Tutor 	2013-2017